자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회
(http://club.korea.com/friends)
안녕
/안녕
Hey, guys / Hey
Hey. What are you doing?
뭐하고 있어?
결혼 계획 세우고 있어
Oh, figuring out our wedding plans
우리도 그거 하고 있었는데
/그러게
-That's funny. We were doing the same thing.
-Yeah.
It's really crazy
예식장이나 드레스하고 음식말야
The hall, the dress, the food, I,
I had no idea how expensive this stuff was
이렇게 비싼줄은 상상도 못했다니까
Yeah, it is really pricey. I mean...
I freaked when I first heard the numbers
그래 정말 비싸
동그라미 갯수 듣고
기절하는 줄 알았다니까
So what did you two do about it?
그래서 너희들은 어떻게 했는데?
사실 생각보다 간단했지
내가 돈을 절약할 계획서를 만들었더니
It was pretty simple actually.
I came up with a couple of cost-cutting solutions,
wrote out a list and
Monica told me to go to hell.
모니카가 지옥에나 가랬지
There is no way around it, Pheebs.
다른 방법은 없어, 피비
You're just going to have to accept the fact
that this is going to cost you a lot of money
그냥 결혼식은 돈이 많이 드는구나 하면 되는거야
I heard the weddings are like
a 40-billion-dollar-a-year industry
어디서 들었는데
결혼산업시장이 1년에 40조원이래
Yeah, and I'm responsible for just like half of that
맞아! 그중 반절은 내가 댔다니깐
Mike, really it does seem like
this money could be put to better use
근데, 결혼자금으로 더 좋은 일을
할 수 있을 것 같지 않아?
정말?
You serious?
Yeah, now how would you feel
if we gave all the wedding money to charity
응, 결혼자금은
자선기금으로 모두 기부하고
and, and we just got married at city hall
우리는 그냥 시청에서
결혼하는건 어때?
I think it would make me want to marry you even more
더 결혼하고 싶어지는데
I've got to say, you guys, that's,
that's an incredible gesture
그거 정말 대단한 생각이다
Maybe you do that next time you get married
그럼 너도 이번에 결혼할때는
그렇게 해봐
안돼~ 이번에는 하와이에서
석양을 받으며 할꺼야
No, no, no, the next time's going to be
Hawaii at sunset.
하지만 그 다음 결혼 때는
한번 생각해볼께
But maybe the time after that
Friends 10x07 TOW Home Study
Transcribed by K. Kim
자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회
(http://club.korea.com/friends)
[ 번 역 ] 김종옥 (joscool76@korea.com)
[ 싱 크 ] 변정주 (jungjoo@kaist.ac.kr)
[ 테스트 ] 윤미내 (minaii@korea.com)
자막에 관련된 문의는 동호회에 있는
'자막 피드백 게시판'으로 해주세요~
안녕
/안녕
Hey / Hey
무슨일 있어?
What's going on?
Our adoption social worker is coming by today
so we're cleaning the apartment
오늘 입양복지사가 집에 온다고 해서
같이 청소하고 있지
"We"?
같이?
You know you don't want me to help
넌 내가 도와주는거 싫어하잖아!
나는 말이라도 해야 할꺼 아냐!
You can't have it both ways!
그럼 그 사람이 입양을 해도
되는지를 결정하는 거야?
Hey, is this the person who decides
whether or not you get a baby?
그럼셈이지,
집에 방문해서 몇가지 질문들을 하고..
Kind of. She's coming by to interview us
and see where we live
모든것이 완벽해야돼!
왜냐하면 그 사람에게 잘못 보이면
And it has to go perfectly
because if she doesn't like something about us,
미국내에서 입양하는 건 불가능이거든
she can keep us off every adoption list in the state.
그럼 나도 잠깐 들러야겠다
Hey, maybe I should stop by.
드라마를 아주 좋아하는
사람일 수도 있잖아!
She could be a soap opera fan.
니들 같은 애들이 연예인 친구가
있다고 하면 기억에 남을꺼야
It's very impressive
when the little people know a celebrity
"Little people"?
우리 같은?
연예인이잖아!
"Celebrity"!
Okay, so I think I'm just about done here, um,
이제 여기는 다 된 것 같아!
unless you have any bad stuff hidden somewhere
like porn or cigarettes?
자기가 어딘가에 포르노나 담배같은걸
숨겨놓지 않았다면 말야
뭐라고?
What?
No!
당근 아니지!
챈들러?
Chandler
I don't and I'm offended by the insinuation
아니래니까!
그건 날 모욕하는 거야!
그래? 그럼 소파 밑에 잡지나
Okay, so there's not a magazine under the couch
화장실 변기 뒤에
테잎으로 담배를 붙여 놨거나
or a pack of cigarettes taped
to the back of the toilet tank.
or a filthy video in the VCR
비디오 안에 난잡한
비디오테입은 없단 말이지?!
I admit to the cigaretts and the magazine
잡지하고 담배는 인정하지!
but that tape is not mine
하지만 그 테입은 내꺼 아냐!
내껀 아니라구!
Well, it isn't mine!
누구껀지 알 수 없을 것 같은데!
I guess we'll never know whose it is
May I help you?
뭘 도와 드릴까요?
네, 어린이를 위해서
조금을 기부하려고요
Yes, we're here to make a
rather sizable donation to the children
Well, any contribution large or small
is always appreciated
기부금이 많건 적건
항상 감사하게 받습니다
Well, I think you're going to appreciate
the crap out of this one
이걸 보시면 아주 많이
감사하다고 생각하실겁니다
Well, this is very generous
상당히 거금이군요!
And we don't want any recognition
익명으로 해주세요
This is completely anonymous
익명으로요!
Completely anonymous.
From two kind strangers
그냥 두 친절한 사람으로부터라고..
Mr. X and Phoebe Buffay
모씨 그리고..
피비부페로 부터라고..
Well, if you like, we can include
your names on our newsletter
원하시면 회보에 이름을 실어드릴께요
-Not necessary
-Buffay is spelled B-u-f-f-a-y
-그럴필요 없어요
-부페는 'ㅂ' 'ㅜ' 'ㅍ' 'ㅔ' 에요
And X is spelled Mike Hannigan
음.. 모씨는..
'마이크 헤니건'이라고 쓰지요
Alright, well, on behalf of the children,
thank you both very much
어린이들을 대신해서
두분께 감사의 말씀을 전합니다.
Sure, I'm so glad we did this
뭘요,착한 일을 하니까
기분도 너무 좋은걸
It feels so good
그래 정말 좋은데!
It does feel really good
이것 좀 봐!
티셔츠를 기념으로 주나봐!
Oh, look, we get this free T-shirt.
아니요, 사실 그 옷은
헬스클럽갈 때 제가 입는 거에요
Uh, actually that's the shirt I wore to the gym
Um, it's moist
어쩐지 좀 축축하더군요
안녕
/ 안녕
Hi / Hey
에마가 조금 있으면 깰꺼야
-Emma will be up in a minute
-Oh, good
그래
Oh, hey , Ross. Listen.
I heard about you and Charlie
참, 찰리하고 잘 안됐다며
I'm really sorry
Oh, that's okay. Actually there are tons of
other beautiful paleontologists out there
괜찮아, 다른 예쁜
고생물학자들도 있겠지뭐
Absolutely
물론이지
단 한명뿐이야!
찰리뿐이었다고!
There was one! She's it!
All the rest look like they should live under a bridge!
다른 여자들은 꼭 다리밑에
사는 사람들 같다니까!
So, uh, what are you going to do today?
어쨌든, 오늘 뭐할꺼야?
Oh, I was thinking of
taking Emma to the playground
놀이터나 갈까 생각중이야
Oh my God. What?
지금 뭐라고 했어?
뭐라고?
Like I said, I was thinking of
taking Emma to the museum of knives and fire.
내가 총칼이 난무하는
전쟁터에라도 간다고 했나?
Okay, look, Ross. I do not want
Emma going to the playground
난 에마가 놀이터에 가는게 싫어
Because?
이.유.는..?
Alright, well, if you must know,
I had a traumatic swing incident when I was little
이유가 그렇게 궁금하다면야..
어렸을 적에
절대 잊을수 없는
그네 사고를 당했었거든
Seriously? / Yes, I was 4 years old
정말?
정말이야!
4살때, 그네를 타고 있었는데..
갑자기 내 머리카락이 그네에 껴버린거야!
and I was on the swing and then
all of a sudden my hair got tangled in the chain
and to get me out, my mom had to,
had to cut a big chunk of my hair
그래서 엄마가 내 머리를
이따만큼이나 잘라야 했다구
그래서 몇주 동안이나
머리가 짝짝이었어
And it was uneven for weeks
And you made it 'through' that?
그 사고에서 살아 남았던거야?
I wonder who's going to play you in the movie.
그걸로 영화나 하나 찍지 그래?
Okay, fine. You can make fun of me.
I do not want Emma going there.
놀릴려면 놀려!
하지만 놀이터에 에마는 못보내!
And I was thinking Claire Danes
"클레어 데인즈"가 주연을 하면..
Look, I'm sorry to hear about your tragedy, okay?
어릴때 아픈기억은 이해 하는데,
그네는 아주 안전한 거라고
But the swings are perfectly safe,
and besides Emma loves them
게다가 에마가 그네타는걸
얼마나 좋아하는지 알아?
You know what?
You should come with us. And you'll see
너도 이참에 같이 가자!
그게 시속 60km나 되는거 알어?
Ross, those things go like 40 miles an hour, okay?
그리고 끝까지 올라가면
and there's this moment when you're at the top,
땅에 다시 돌아오지 못할 것
같은 기분이 든다구!
you just don't know
if you're going to return back to earth!
Space 'is' filled with orbiting children
놀이터에 애들이 떠다니겠구나!
Look, please. Just, just come on, you know?
그러지 말고 같이 가자!
가서 에마가 즐거워하는 걸 보면
When you see the look on Emma's face,
I swear you won't regret it
마음이 달라질꺼라니까
Alright / Good
알았어
잘 생각 했어
You know, you don't want to be one of those mothers
엄마가 바보 같이 무서워하는걸
에마한테 물려주고 싶은건 아니지?
who pass on their irrational fears
to their children, do you?
Irrational, huh?
바보같이? 그래?
Alright, I'll remember that the next time
you freak out about a spider in your apartment.
다음에 너가 거미보고
까무라치는거 보면 똑같이 말해주지
Oh, yeah. That's the same, I'm sure there are
30 different species of poisonous swings
어떻게 거미랑 그네를 비교해?
그네 중에도 독이 있는
그네가 30종류는 되나보지?
어머, 입양복지사가 일찍 왔나봐
Oh my God. The adoption lady's early.
괜찮아, 괜찮아
이제부터 시작이라구..
Okay, okay. Here we go.
Stand up straight
똑바로 서고!
Big smile
환하게 웃어!
Hello, is this the creepy residence?
어, 안녕하세요?
여기가 "바보"씨 댁인가요?
입양복지사를 기다리고 있거든
We're waiting for the adoption lady
but , hey, I'm glad you're here
마침 잘왔어. 아침에
청소를 하다가 이걸 발견했거든..
I was cleaning this morning and I found this
니가 이걸 쓰고
싶을지는 모르겠지만
I don't know if you want to use it but...
Oh, this is so sweet of you. Oh
역시 너밖에 없다
근데 면사포가 필요없을것 같아
사실 웨딩드레스도 안입을지 몰라
but you know what?
I won't be needing a veil
I actually won't be wearing a dress at all
전에 말했잖아!
난 절대로 누드결혼식에는 안간다니까!
I told you I am not coming to a naked wedding!
No, no, no. We're just,
we're not having a big reception.
아니 그게 아니라
성대한 피로연 같은걸 안한다는거야
결혼에다 쓸려고 했던 돈을
어린이 기금에다가 기부했거든
We took the money we're going to spend on the wedding
and we donated it to a children's charity
너 미쳤어?
That's crazy!
미안. 하지만 일생에 한번뿐인
결혼식을 그렇게 하면 어떡하니?
I'm sorry. I just, I can't imagine
giving up my one wedding day like that
그게 너네하고 우리하고 차이라니까!
Yeah, well, we're different, you know?
I don't care about having a huge party
그런 큰 파티가 무슨 소용이야
이거 니가 썼을때는 정말 예뻤지만
This is really nice for you but...
내가 이거 쓰면..아마도..
Oh, please, I'll put this on and
,ugh, I just look like
well, radiant!
어라 눈부신데?
Alright, but who cares? You know?
"예쁜" 면사포랑 "휘황찬란"한
웨딩드레스가 무슨 소용이야..
I don't need a pretty veil and a fancy dress
That's right. You're making a commitment and ...
그래 니말이 맞아!
결혼은 서약을 하는 거지!
You know, that's the same
whether you do it at the plaza or...
장소가 무슨 상관이야
플라자에서 하든 아니면..
넌 어디서 할건데?
where were you going to do it?
City hall. / Oh~
시청
맙.. 머.. 멋진곳에서 하네!
Oh, that sounds nice
나는 거기 배심원 하러 갔었거든..
You know, I was just there for jury duty.
They've really spruced that place up
꽤 깔끔하게 꾸며놨더라구
Okay, no, it's okay.
괜찮아.. 안돼.. 괜찮아..
It's okay, it's okay
I've made my decision.
What I really want is a...
이제 결정했다!
내가 정말 원하는 것은
아주 성대하고 휘황찬란한 결혼식이야!
great big wedding! Huh!
봐!
Yay!
근데, 너 그 돈을 벌써 기부해 버렸잖아!
But you already gave all the money to charity.
Well, I'll just ask for it back
그냥 돌려달라고 하지 뭐!
I don't think you can do that
그건 안될껄?
Why not? This is her wedding day
왜? 피비의 결혼식이라고!
이게 그 멍청한 애들보다는 훨씬 중요한 일이잖아!
That's way more important than some stupid kids
That's sweet, honey
but save something for the adoption lady
자기 그말 아주 맘에 드네!
조금후에 입양복지사 오면 한마디 해줘!
Okay
알았어
Alright, okay, be careful
괜찮아
조심해
머리 조심하고
Okay / Careful
Watch her hair. Watch her hair!
머리 조심하라구!
-Rach, she's got like three hairs
-I know, I know
이봐, 머리카락도 별로 없어!
알아 안다구
하지만 머리결이 얼마나 좋은데!
but they're just so beautiful
Oh my God, I just pulled one out
어머나, 한개 뽑아 버렸네..
괜찮다니까!
잘봐, 에마가 얼마나 좋아하는지 잘 보라구
I promise you she's safe, okay?
Now watch!
Watch how much she loves this.
알았어
-Okay, okay
-Are you ready, sweetie? Here we go
우리 아가 준비 됐어?
자 시작한다~
Okay, careful
조심해!
She's smiling
우리아가가 웃네!
정말 그네를 좋아하네
Oh, look at that! She does like it
See? I told you.
거봐! 내가 그랬잖아
Oh my God! Look at her.
She's a little daredevil
세상에나.. 무섭지도 않은가봐!
Oh, God! Oh, let me push.
Can I push?
내가 밀어볼래!
밀어봐도 되?
Oh, absolutely / Okay
물론이지!
Okay, get, get the camera.
It's, it's in the diaper bag.
카메라 준비해
기저귀 가방에 있어
Okay
알았어
See? Scared of the swings
거봐 그네를 무서워해?
너도 그말한게 좀 우습다고 생각되지?
I bet you feel pretty silly
정말 돈 돌려달라고 할꺼야?
We're seriously asking for the money back?
결혼자금이잖아!
It's for our wedding day
Alright, now. Is this guy gay or straight?
저 사람 게이일까 아닐까?
우리 둘중 하나가 좀 수작을 걸어봐야 할꺼 아냐
Cause one of us's going to have to start flirting
Wow! You're here to make
another donation the same day?
아니, 오늘 또 기부금을 내시게요?
아직까지 그런 일은 없었는데요
I don't think that's ever happened before
Gay, go!
게이다
니가 해!
Oh my God! I love your shirt
셔츠가 참 잘 어울리시네요
어.. 아까 기부한 돈 있잖아요..
돌려주시면 안될까요?
The donation we made earlier, um...
well, we want, we want it back
Excuse me?
뭐라구요?
그러니까, 그돈은
사실 저희 결혼자금이었거든요
Yeah, see, okay.
That money was for a big wedding that we thought
we didn't want but it turns out we do
성대한 결혼식을 안하려구 했는데
하고 싶어졌어요
그래서, 기부한 돈을
환불해달라는 말인가요?
So you're asking us to refund
your donation to the children?
Yeah
그렇죠!
This feels really good
이것도 기분 정말 좋은데?
죄송해요, 하지만 이 결혼식이
저한테는 정말 중요하거든요
Yeah, I'm so, I'm sorry. I am.
But you know this wedding's
just really important to me
Hey, it's none of my business
제가 상관할바는 아니죠!
게다가 이게 오히려 더 좋을 수도 있거든요
Besides, this is probably a good thing
We've really been spoiling the children
with all the food and warm clothing
이 돈으로 아이들에게 좋은 음식과 따뜻한 옷을
사주면, 애들 성질을 버릴수도 있을테니까요
That's not fair!
아니 말을 왜 그렇게 하세요?
결혼식이란건 중요한거에요
A person's wedding is important
and it's especially to me!
특히 저한테는 더더욱요. 전 졸업파티도 못해봤고 댄스파티도 못가봤어요
Okay? I, I didn't have a graduation party
and I didn't go to prom.
And I, and I spent my sweet 16
being chased around a tire yard
저의 꽃다운 16살때는 정신병원에서
탈출한 사람한테 쫓겨 다녔다구요
by an ...escaped mental patient,
who, in his own words, "wanted to kill me" or whatever.
그 사람은 자기 입으로
"날 죽이고 싶어서" 그랬다고 했다구요
So I deserve a real celebration.
그러니까 이 정도는
할 수 있는 거 아닌가요?
And, and I'm, I'm not going to let some sweaty little man
make me feel badly about it.
별것도 아닌 땀냄새 나는 사람이
그 기분을 알아요?
She could've been talking about either one of us
그게 꼭 당신을 두고
하는 말은 아니에요
Hi, I'm Laura. I'm here for your adoption interview.
안녕하세요, 전 로라라고 해요
입양면접심사하러 왔는데요
Hi, I'm Monica and this is Chandler / Hi
안녕하세요. 전 모니카에요
이쪽은 챈들러이구요
들어오세요
Please come in / Thank you
감사합니다
Would you like something to drink?
마실것 좀 드릴까요?
Oh, water would be fine.
물 한잔만 주세요
물론이죠
여기까지 와주셔서 정말 감사해요
Okay, great. I'm so glad that you are here
We're really excited about getting this process started
저희는 입양절차가 시작되는
것만으로 기쁘거든요
Because we love kids
Love 'em to death
저희가 아이들을 정말 좋아하거든요
아이들이 좋아 죽겠어요
아니 정말 죽겠다는게 아니고
Well, not actually to death.
That's just a figure of speech
말하자면 그렇다는 거죠!
We love kids the appropriate amount
저희는 적당히 애들을 좋아해요
As allowed by law
법이 허락하는 내에서요
Your place is just lovely
집이 아주 멋지네요
Ah, thank you
고마워요. 이 건물자체가
건전하고 가정적인 느낌이 있죠
Yes, this building does have
a wholesome family feel to it
근데 왠지 이 건물에 와 본 적이 있는 것 같아요
혹시 입양하려고 하는 다른 부부가 사나요?
You know, I, I feel like I've been here before
Are any other couples in the building adopting?
혹시 1층에 사는
그 부부를 말하는 건가요?
Is that that couple on the first floor?
Because we should get a baby before them!
왜냐하면 그 사람들보다
우리가 먼저 입양을 해야 해요
That guy tried to sell me drugs!
그 사람이 저한테
약을 팔려고 하더라구요!
But other than that,
wholesome, wholesome building
하지만 그것을 제외하고는
건전한, 건전한 동네죠
Oh
아!
왜요?
What?
I just realized why I remember this place
그냥 제가 이 곳이
낯익은지 생각났거든요
정말요? 왜 그런데요?
Really? What is it?
Oh, it's nothing.
I went on a date with a guy who lived in this building
별거 아니에요
예전에 여기사는 어떤 남자랑
데이트를 했는데 끝이 별로 않좋았거든요
and it didn't end very well
Ugh, that wouldn't by any chance
be Joey Tribbiani.
설마 조이 트리비아니는 아니겠죠?
Oh, yes!
맞아요!
Of course it was.
물론 그렇겠죠
Yeah, we had a really great night and
정말 괜찮은 밤을 보내고나서, 저한테
전화한다고 약속해놓고는 안했다니까요
in the morning he promised he would call me and he didn't
Rat Bastard!
이런 쥐새끼 같은놈!
So you're not friends with him?
그 사람하고는 안 친한가 보죠?
오노! 절대 아니죠
Oh, God, no! / No, no, no, no.
아뇨~ 아뇨아뇨아뇨~ 아뇨~ 아뇨!
No! Nope...... / No, no, no,no....
Well, I'm sorry I brought it up
괜히 그런 얘길 꺼내서 죄송해요
So, are either one of you planning on
staying at home with the child?
두분 중 어느 한 분이
집에서 아이를 돌보실 계획이신가..
Hello
안에 누구 없어?
혹시 "연예인"을 주문한 사람 없나?
Anybody in there ordered a celebrity?
Ow!
What was that?
뭐죠?
Oh, that's just some crazy guy who roams the halls here
그냥 여기 복도에서 서성거리는 정신나간
사람이에요. 하지만 애들한테는 무척 잘해요!
He's great with kids though
Oh, God, Ross. Oh my God! Are you okay?
하나님 맙소사! 괜찮아?
Son of a bitch!
이런 개자식!
Oh, relax ! I didn't say the F word.
뭐 어때서
쌍시옷은 안들어 가잖아!
내가 말했잖아!
그네는 악마라니까!
Ross, see, I told you the swings are evil!
Alright. That is it!
이제 됐어
That is the last time Emma is getting on
one of those things for her entire life
이번이 마지막이야
다시는 그네 안태워!
아니야! 그네 잘못이 아니었다고
No, no, no, no, no. Okay.
It wasn't the swing's fault. It was my fault.
내 잘못이었어
그리고 저 꼬마녀석 잘못도 있고..
And kind of that kid's fault
who is still laughing. Nice
근데 계속 웃고 있네
Ross, come on, please. Can we just get out of here
before somebody else gets hurt?
또 다른 사람 다치기전에 돌아가자!
안돼! 알았어
좋은 생각이 떠올랐어
No, wait, okay, okay. I have an idea.
I want you to get on the swing, okay?
너가 직접 그네를 타보는 거야
그러면 분명 더이상 그네가 무섭지 않을거라구
And, and you'll see that there's nothing to be afraid of.
알았다, 니가 왜 나한테 이러는지..
넌 항상 내 머리결을 부러워 해왔던거구나
I know what this is all about.
You've always been jealous of my hair
Look, I just think you're an adult, okay?
너도 이제 어른이잖아!
그런 바보같은 두려움증은 없애야지!
And you, you should get over your silly fears
그래 그렇게 하지!
Alright, fine! I'll do it! / Good
좋았어
만약에 니가 거미를 잡으면!
If you hold the spider.
What? Where? Where?
어디! 어디에!
"IF" you hold a spider.
만약! 니가 거미를 잡고 있으면!
나도 알아
I know
Guys, is everything okay?
얘들아? 괜찮은 거야?
나라고 나! 조~
It's me, Joey! / Ah ah~
아~~~~~
A.....doption!
입양!
What's going on?
왜그러시는 거에요?
Oh, just like I said, that crazy.... Bert roaming the halls
아까 말씀드린대로,
그 미친 "버트"가 복도에서 서성거리거든요
이봐!
Guys / Keep on roaming, Bert!
계속 돌아다녀!
오늘은 니가 없어도 되
We don't want any crazy today!
What's going on?
무슨 일이야!
We'll talk to you later, Bert. Everything's fine!
아무일 없으니까 나중에 얘기해!
Everything doesn't sound fine.
아무일 없는 소리가 아니잖아!
Is he alright out there by himself?
그사람 혼자 놔둬도 괜찮아요?
괜찮아요
그 사람 돌봐주는 형이 있거든요
Oh, yeah. He has a caretaker, his older brother.
Ernie
"어니"요
Bert and Ernie?
"버트와 어니"요?
You can't make this stuff up!
지어내기도 힘들죠!
You never told me about that guy
자기 나한테 꽃다운 16살때 당한일 이야기 한적 없잖아?
그런 일이 있었단 말이야?
On your sweet sixteen? Oh, I'm sorry about that.
괜찮아 끝은 좋았거든
내 친구중에 하나가 쏴버렸거든
Oh, it ended okay. One of my friends shot him
Well, hey, at least you're getting a proper wedding.
어쨌든 제대로 된 결혼식은 할 수 있게 됐잖아
내 말은 자긴 그럴만한 자격이 있다는 말이야
I mean you deserve that.
나도 알아! 난 제대로
해본게 하나도 없었어
Yeah, I really do, you know?
I had nothing growing up.
내가 돈을 뺏은
마치 아까 말한 그 아이들 처럼..
Just like the kids I took the money from.
No, no, no.
안돼, 그러지마
I see where this is going.
Don't make me go back there.
자기가 무슨말을 할려는지 알아
거기 다시 가고 싶지 않아
그돈으로 결혼하는 건 불가능할 것
같아. 이미 부정탄 돈이잖아!
Look, I can't have a wedding
with this money now. It's tainted
알았어.. 돈 다시 돌려주지 뭐!
Alright, fine. We'll give the money back.
And if that guy at the charity gives us a hard time,
만약 그 기금 접수원이 뭐라고 그러면..
내 친구 총 안 쏜지 정말 오래됐으니까..
my friend hasn't shot anyone in a really~ long time.
Well, I must say this seems like
a lovely environment to raise a child in
아이들을 키우기에
아주 좋은 환경인 것 같아요
아참, 원하시면 가구 밑
같은 곳을 보셔도 괜찮아요
Oh, by the way, you're more than welcome
to look under any of the furniture
because, believe me, you won't find
any porn or cigarettes under there.
거기에 포르노나 담배같은건
절대 없거든요
Oh, actually, before we look around,
let me make sure I have everything I need up to here.
돌아보기 전에 다른 필요사항들을
다 체크했는지 확인 좀 해볼께요
Why don't I show you the baby's room?
애기방 좀 보실래요?
너 지금 뭐하는 거야?
What the hell are you doing?
Well, you wouldn't let me in
so I thought you were in trouble!
니가 안들여 보내 주길래
무슨 문제가 있는줄 알았지!
Well, we're not!
그런거 없어!
But you called me Bert!
근데 니가 나를 '버트'라고 불렀잖아!
그게 위험에 빠졌다는 암호잖아!
That's our code word for danger!
암호 같은 거 없어!
We don't have a code word! / We don't?
없어?
We really should
그럼 하나 만들자!
이제부터 '버트'가 "위험"의 암호명이야!
From now on, Bert will be our code word for danger.
여기까지 애기방이었구요..
이제 어느 방을 봐야 할 차례지?
So that was the baby's room
Ah, what room should we see next?
Any room that isn't behind this couch.
이 쇼파 뒤에 있는
방만 아니면 다 좋아
어떤 사람은 저런 유머를 이해 못하는데요
정말 재밌지 않나요?
Some people don't get him
but I think he's really funny.
나 그런거 별로 안 좋아해!
I did not care for that
You have to get out of here!
여기서 빨리 나가야해!
You slept with our social worker
and you never called her back!
니가 저 복지사랑 자고 나서
전화를 안했었다고 하더라고!
그리고 아직 그 일로 화나있고
그러니까 빨리 사라져!
And she is still pissed so she can't see you!
알았어! 알았어!
Oh, well, okay, okay
뭐야?
What?
방망이를 까먹었어
I forgot my bat.
Oh my God!
하나님 맙소사
마지막으로 다시 말하지만
당신과 친구가 되고 싶은 생각 없다니까요!
And for the last time,
we do not want to be friends with you!
And we don't want to buy your bat!
그리고 야구방망이도 안 사요!
여기서 뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing here?
Bert, Bert, Bert.
'버트(위험)' '버트' '버트'
Are you friends with him?
저 사람하고 친구사이에요?
I can explain
제가 설명할께요..
Joey.
조이!
알았어..
Ah, okay, uh,...
Oh, yeah.
You have got some nerve coming back here
당신 아주 용기있군요
여길 다시 돌아오다니!
I can't believe you never called me!
어떻게 나한테 전화를 안 할 수 있지?
Excuse me?
뭐라고?
Oh, yeah.
허~ 아마 내 이름도 기억 못하고 있을껄?
말해두지만 "조이"야!
Probably you don't even remember my name!
It's Joey, by the way.
And don't bother telling me yours
because I totally remember it
그리고 당신 이름은 말할 필요 없어
당신 이름은 절대 잊을수 없었거든
Lady
아가씨!
Yeah. I waited weeks for you to call me
내가 몇주동안이나
당신 전화를 기다렸는지 알아?
I gave you my number. You never called me.
내 전화번호 알려줬잖아!
그리고 당신이 전화 안한거야!
No, don't try to turn this around on me, okay?
일을 내 탓으로 돌리려고 하지마!
난..그러니까 복지가가 아니라구
I am not some kind of.... social work, okay?
그냥.. 그런 일을 하는!
that you can just ....do
Well, I'm pretty sure I gave you my number / Really?
당신한테 전화번호 줬다니까!
정말? 생각해보라구..
Think about it. Come on.
You're a beautiful woman, smart, funny.
We had a really good time, huh?
당신은 아름답고, 똑똑하고, 유머까지 갖추었고
게다가 아주 즐거운 시간을 함께했는데..
If I had your number, why wouldn't I call you?
내가 전화번호가 있었으면
왜 전화를 안했겠어?
I don't know
나도 모르지
Oh, maybe I'm wrong. I'm sorry
내가 틀렸을 수도 있고
그랬다면 미안해
No, no, you know, too late for apologies, okay?
사과를 받아들이기엔 너무 늦었어!
나한테 상처를 줬다고!
You broke my heart
You know how many women I had to sleep with
to get over you?
당신을 잊기 위해 얼마나 많은
여자들과 자야했는지 알아?
Joey, wait! / No!
조이! 기다려!
/싫어!
난 오랬동안 기다렸었어..
더이상은 기다릴수 없다고!
I waited a long time. I can't wait any more
I'm sorry that you had to see this
I'm so embarrassed
죄송해요, 이런 모습 보여드려서
정말 창피하네요
괜찮아요
Oh, that's really okay
Yeah, I mean we totally understand. Dating is hard
저도 이해해요
남녀관계라는것이 쉬운것이 아니죠
정말 친절하시군요
Boy, you people are nice
and I've got to say
제 생각에 두분은 아주
I think you're going to make excellent parents
훌륭한 부모님이 되실수 있을것 같아요
Laura!
로~ 라~!
저희 또 왔어요
We're back
Are you here to take more money?
돈을 더 드릴까요?
제 생각에 두분이 찾으시는 것은
현금지급기인것 같아서요
Because I think what you're looking for is an ATM
No, no, we're here to give the money back
아뇨. 그 돈 다시 기부하려구요
Yeah, because you know what? It's ...
맞아요
아이들이 더 중요하죠
it's all about the children
Although... it's also about the wedding
하지만 결혼식도 중요하고..
Ugh, here, no. Oh, God!
여기요, 아냐..
If I haven't said so already, sir, congratulations
제가 말씀드렸었나요?
결혼 축하드려요!
Okay, look, enough! Alright?
이제 그만해!
I'm stepping in and I put my foot down
당신의 미래의 남편으로써
내가 단호하게 결정을 내릴테니까!
As your future husband,
I'm going to make this decision for us
No, what do you think we should do?
어떻게 했으면 좋겠어?
You know what?
이거보세요. 제가 결정해 드리죠!
/ 뭐라구요?
It's not your decision any more. / What?
뉴욕의 아이들을 대신해서
당신들의 기부금을 거절하겠습니다
On behalf of the children of New York,
I reject your money
하지만, 기부할래요
But we're, we're giving you this.
하지만, 돌려드릴께요.
And I'm giving it back to you
Come on. Consider it a contribution.
기부금이라고 생각하세요
Oh, this is very generous
정말 큰돈이네요
Please take the check.
Go have a great wedding and a wonderful life together.
수표 가져가시구요
멋진 결혼식 하셔서 행복하게 사세요
Well, I mean, it sounds good to me.
괜찮은 생각인 것 같은데
That way we can save up, come back in a few years,
그럼 앞으로 저축해서
이자쳐서 기부하면 되지뭐!
and make an even bigger donation / Absolutely
물론이죠!
And when you do, make sure you ask for Brian.
그때는 꼭 브라이언을 찾으세요!
Oh, is that you? / No
당신 성함이세요?
/ 아니요!
Hello.
여보세요?
아, 안녕하세요?
Oh, hi.
Oh my God! Really?
세상에! 정말요?
챈들러도 아주 기뻐할꺼에요!
I can't wait to tell Chandler
Okay, good bye.
네, 그럼
잘못 걸려온 전화야?
Wrong number?
It was Laura
로라였어.
보고서를 아주 잘 써줬대
그래서 공식적으로 대기자 명단에 올랐대
She gave us a great report
and we are officially on the waiting list
That's great!
정말 잘됐다!
Yeah, we just have to wait for a call and,
and someone tells us there's a baby waiting for us
이제 아이가 기다리고 있으니
데려가라는 전화만 기다리면 된다구
오
Oh
여보세요?
Hello
조이 야구방망이 봤어?
Have you seen Joey's bat?
Have you enjoyed watching Friends?^^
You can distribute this file WITHOUT prior consent with me
Okay.
자
I got a spider
거미는 준비 됐어!
두마리 있었는데
큰놈으로 잡아왔지
There were two. I picked the bigger one
알았어
/ 자
Okay / Okay
This feels perfectly normal
이거 느낌이 아주.. 정상인데?
Okay, get on the swing
이제 그네에 올라타
Okay
그래
알았어.. 알았다구
O-kay
Okay
알았어
See?
괜찮지?
Ah, alright. I can do this
괜찮은데
할만해!
There you go. Good for you!
거봐, 잘하잖아
왠지 이녀석한테도 적응이 되는 것 같아!
You know what?
I'm actually getting used to this little guy
I don't really even feel him in here any more
손 안에 있는 것 같지도 않은데?
That's because it's on your neck
그거야 네 목에 있으니까 그렇지!
What?!
아~악~
Ross!
로스~